RAJAT KUMAR

Madrid, Spain | (+34) 670 899 097 | rajat@student.ie.edu | linkedin.com/in/rajatasusual INDIAN CITIZENSHIP | Eligible for an Internship in EU

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Engineering Consultant with 6+ years experience in developing complex IT products for multiple domains - Automation, Compliance & Financial Regulations working for MNCs in tech and finance industries. Led Digital Transformation project teams for the Finances team across London, Australia and South Asia with a budget scope totalling €330k: Full stack architectural solutions, Client Management and Budget Management.

EDUCATION

IE Business School Madrid, Spain

International MBA – Master's in Business Administration

JAN. 2021 - DEC. 2022 (EXPECTED)

• Recipient of Science & Innovation Scholarship.

INDRAPRASTHA UNIVERSITY

NEW DELHI, INDIA

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

Aug. 2011 - Jun. 2015

- Founding member and Secretary, Computer Society of India Student Chapter.
- Paper on Evolution of Ubiquitous Computing ISBN No. 978-93-83083-54-1.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOCIÉTÉ GÉNÉRALE (INVESTMENT BANK, \$24BN)

BANGALORE, INDIA

French multinational investment bank and financial services company headquartered in Paris, France.

Specialist Software Engineer - Engineering Consultant

Jul. 2019- Nov. 2021

- Consulted Finance teams in London and Singapore, Hong Kong and Australia regions on engineering solutions.
- Spearheaded a team to digitally transform regulation compliance for the Client Assets team decreased turnaround time by 39% and reporting errors by 15%.
- Reduced annual billing cost by €38k. (28%) and carbon footprint by 52% Received SPOT award (given to 7 people per quarter across development divisions globally) for migration towards Open-Source services.
- Conceptualized and headed project for Application merger reducing infrastructure billing by €73k (34%) annually.

SMARSH Co. (COMPLIANCE, \$150MN IN REVENUES)

BANGALORE, INDIA

The global leader in compliance & enterprise info. archiving, serves 7000+ financial services firms.

Senior Software Engineer – Full Stack Developer

May. 2016 – Jul. 2019

- Developed Connected Archive, world's largest archival solution, as core engineer for Application team. Clientele include top banks and financial institutions across America and Europe.
- Received Star Performer award for automating testing framework decreasing application qualification time by 67%.
- Initiated and collaborated on CSR path in company, leading efforts to reach out to NGOs for collaboration.

QUEST GLOBAL (PRODUCT ENGINEERING, \$2.5BN)

BANGALORE, INDIA

Selected by Gartner as one of the leading vendors in multiple technologies, Company of the year 2013 by CIO Review.

Software Engineer – Application Development

Aug. 2015 – May. 2016

- Engineered for team working on a patented Robotic Process Automation product, Fusion.
- Presented with Letter of Recommendation from Vice Chairman for consistent effort towards delivery of new product.
- Implemented template-based coding practice facilitating in shortening developer's time by 50%.

LANGUAGES & SKILLS

English (advanced); Hindi (native); Spanish (beginner)

Full Stack Development | System Architecture | Public Speaking

Certified Agile Practitioner | Certified Lean Six Sigma – Black Belt (Technology processes)

OTHER INFORMATION

- Volunteer for Make A Difference (*NGO working towards equitable outcome for children living in shelter homes across India*) Teacher (2016-17) for 6th standard children, Mentor (2017-18) for 30 volunteers, City Manager (2018-19) for Education Support Programme for Bangalore (includes 300+ volunteers) and Fundraising volunteer (2019-20).
- Harvard CORe Credential 4-month program comprising of three courses Business Analytics, Economics, and Financial Accounting. Passed with high honours (90 Percentile).
- Toastmasters International (2019-2021) Secretary (2019), VP Membership (2020), VP Education (2021). Winner of International Speech Contest at District, Area and club level.